<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?asciidoc-toc?>
<?asciidoc-numbered?>
<article xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:lang="en">
<info>
<title>CDP Certification Process</title>
<date>2023-03-01</date>
<authorgroup>
<author>
<personname>
<firstname>Puneet</firstname>
<surname>Joshi</surname>
</personname>
<email>puneetjoshi@cloudera.com</email>
</author>
<author>
<personname>
<firstname>Pannag</firstname>
<surname>Katti</surname>
</personname>
<email>pkatti@cloudera.com</email>
</author>
</authorgroup>
</info>
<simpara role="data-line-4">1.0, Feb 22, 2023</simpara>
<simpara role="data-line-6">This document provides the details for Partners who are willing to integrate and validate their product (ISV) and hardware (IHV) on Cloudera Data Platform(CDP). Cloudera Data Platform  is a single platform that has two form factors CDP Public and CDP Private cloud.</simpara>
<section xml:id="_introduction" role="data-line-8">
<title>Introduction</title>
<simpara role="data-line-10"><emphasis role="strong">CDP Public Cloud</emphasis> is an integrated analytics and data management platform deployed on <emphasis role="strong">cloud services</emphasis>. It consists of a number of cloud services designed to address specific enterprise data cloud use cases.
This includes Data Hub powered by Cloudera Runtime, self-service experiences (Data Warehouse, Machine Learning, and Data Engineering) running on containers, the administrative layer (Management Console), and SDX services (Data Lake, Data Catalog, Replication Manager, and Workload Manager).</simpara>
<simpara role="data-line-13"><emphasis role="strong">CDP Private Cloud</emphasis> is an integrated analytics and data management platform deployed in <emphasis role="strong">private data centers</emphasis>. It consists of CDP Private Cloud Base and CDP Private Cloud Data Services and offers broad data analytics and artificial intelligence functionality along with secure user access and data governance features.</simpara>
<simpara><?asciidoc-hr?></simpara>
<simpara role="data-line-17">This document outlines the steps to validate/integrate on CDP for,</simpara>
<itemizedlist role="data-line-20">
<listitem role="data-line-20">
<simpara>Independent Software Vendors <emphasis role="strong">(ISV)</emphasis> Partners who are willing to integrate their software products and validate it on any one of the CDP form factors or on both.</simpara>
</listitem>
<listitem role="data-line-22">
<simpara>Independent Hardware Vendors <emphasis role="strong">(IHV)</emphasis> Partners who are willing to validate and test CDP Private Cloud form factor on their hardware.</simpara>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</section>
<section xml:id="_register_on_cloudera_sso" role="data-line-25">
<title>Register on Cloudera SSO</title>
<simpara role="data-line-27"><emphasis>(<emphasis role="strong">Skip the below steps and jump to <xref linkend="partner_portal_access"/> if you are already registered on Cloudera SSO.</emphasis>)</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara role="data-line-29"><emphasis role="strong"><phrase role="underline">Step1:</phrase></emphasis> Register yourself and your team members who will be working on this certification engagement in Cloudera SSO by accessing the below URL.</simpara>
<simpara role="data-line-31"><link xl:href="https://sso.cloudera.com/">https://sso.cloudera.com/</link></simpara>
<informalfigure role="data-line-33">
<mediaobject>
<imageobject>
<imagedata fileref="images/Register_to_SSO.png"/>
</imageobject>
<textobject><phrase>Register to SSO</phrase></textobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<note role="data-line-35">
<simpara>Make sure registration is done by using an official email id.</simpara>
</note>
<informalfigure role="data-line-37">
<mediaobject>
<imageobject>
<imagedata fileref="images/Registration_Details.png"/>
</imageobject>
<textobject><phrase>Registration Details</phrase></textobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara role="data-line-39"><emphasis role="strong"><phrase role="underline">Step 2:</phrase></emphasis> An activation code will be sent over the email. Please verify each registered email id by following the steps mentioned in that email.</simpara>
<simpara role="data-line-41"><emphasis role="strong"><phrase role="underline">Step 3:</phrase></emphasis> After verification of the email id, you will be redirected to profile creation page. Please submit the required details to  complete the <emphasis role="strong">SSO</emphasis> account creation.</simpara>
</section>
<section xml:id="partner_portal_access" role="data-line-43">
<title>Register on Cloudera Partner Portal</title>
<simpara role="data-line-45"><emphasis role="strong"><phrase role="underline">Step1:</phrase></emphasis> Please submit the form available at below URL.</simpara>
<simpara role="data-line-47"><link xl:href="https://www.cloudera.com/partners/membership-application.html">https://www.cloudera.com/partners/membership-application.html</link></simpara>
<informalfigure role="data-line-49">
<mediaobject>
<imageobject>
<imagedata fileref="images/Partner_Portal_Apply.png"/>
</imageobject>
<textobject><phrase>Partner Portal Apply</phrase></textobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara role="data-line-51"><emphasis>If prompted, login with your Cloudera SSO account.</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara role="data-line-53"><emphasis role="strong"><phrase role="underline">Step 2:</phrase></emphasis> Select the Primary Line Of Business field.</simpara>
<itemizedlist role="data-line-56">
<listitem role="data-line-56">
<simpara>If you are an <emphasis role="strong">ISV Partner</emphasis> select “Software Vendor/ISV” in the Primary Line Of Business field.</simpara>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<informalfigure role="data-line-58">
<mediaobject>
<imageobject>
<imagedata fileref="images/Select_ISV.png"/>
</imageobject>
<textobject><phrase>Select ISV</phrase></textobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<itemizedlist role="data-line-60">
<listitem role="data-line-60">
<simpara>If you are an <emphasis role="strong">IHV Partner</emphasis> select “Hardware Vendor/IHV” in the Primary Line Of Business field.</simpara>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<informalfigure role="data-line-62">
<mediaobject>
<imageobject>
<imagedata fileref="images/Select_IHV.png"/>
</imageobject>
<textobject><phrase>Select IHV</phrase></textobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
<simpara role="data-line-65"><emphasis role="strong"><phrase role="underline">Step 3:</phrase></emphasis> Submit the application.</simpara>
<simpara role="data-line-67">Once the above application is approved you will be notified over the email containing the URL to access the <emphasis role="strong">Partner Portal</emphasis>.</simpara>
</section>
<section xml:id="_request_for_development_license" role="data-line-69">
<title>Request For Development License</title>
<simpara role="data-line-71">Once the access to Partner Portal is approved, please follow the below steps.</simpara>
<orderedlist role="data-line-73" numeration="arabic">
<listitem role="data-line-73">
<simpara>Access the Partner Portal by using below url:</simpara>
<simpara role="data-line-75"><link xl:href="https://cloudera-portal.force.com/clouderapartners/s/">https://cloudera-portal.force.com/clouderapartners/s/</link></simpara>
</listitem>
<listitem role="data-line-77">
<simpara>Navigate to <emphasis role="strong"><emphasis>Technical</emphasis></emphasis> dropdown and select <emphasis role="strong"><emphasis>Developer License Request</emphasis></emphasis>.</simpara>
<informalfigure role="data-line-79">
<mediaobject>
<imageobject>
<imagedata fileref="images/Dropdown_Portal.png"/>
</imageobject>
<textobject><phrase>Dropdown Portal</phrase></textobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
</listitem>
<listitem role="data-line-81">
<simpara>Fill in the required details:</simpara>
<orderedlist role="data-line-83" numeration="loweralpha">
<listitem role="data-line-83">
<simpara>Cloudera Contact(s) that you are working with</simpara>
</listitem>
<listitem role="data-line-84">
<simpara>What Cloudera product are you requesting?(<emphasis role="strong">Choose one</emphasis>)</simpara>
<itemizedlist role="data-line-85">
<listitem role="data-line-85">
<simpara>CDP Public Cloud</simpara>
</listitem>
<listitem role="data-line-86">
<simpara>CDSW</simpara>
</listitem>
<listitem role="data-line-87">
<simpara>Data Flow</simpara>
</listitem>
<listitem role="data-line-88">
<simpara>HDP</simpara>
</listitem>
<listitem role="data-line-89">
<simpara>Data Plane</simpara>
</listitem>
<listitem role="data-line-90">
<simpara>CDH</simpara>
</listitem>
<listitem role="data-line-91">
<simpara>Private Cloud Base</simpara>
</listitem>
<listitem role="data-line-92">
<simpara>Private Cloud Data Services</simpara>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</listitem>
<listitem role="data-line-94">
<simpara>Reason for request</simpara>
</listitem>
</orderedlist>
</listitem>
<listitem role="data-line-97">
<simpara>Click Next and Submit</simpara>
</listitem>
</orderedlist>
<simpara role="data-line-99"><emphasis>(PS: It takes a couple of days for the request to get processed from here.)</emphasis></simpara>
</section>
<section xml:id="_for_isv_partners" role="data-line-103">
<title>For ISV Partners</title>
<section xml:id="_submit_isv_certification_request" role="data-line-105">
<title>Submit ISV Certification Request</title>
<orderedlist role="data-line-107" numeration="arabic">
<listitem role="data-line-107">
<simpara>Access the Partner Portal by using below url:</simpara>
<simpara role="data-line-109"><link xl:href="https://cloudera-portal.force.com/clouderapartners/s/">https://cloudera-portal.force.com/clouderapartners/s/</link></simpara>
</listitem>
<listitem role="data-line-111">
<simpara>Navigate to <emphasis role="strong">Technical</emphasis> dropdown and select <emphasis role="strong">Product Certification</emphasis>.</simpara>
<informalfigure role="data-line-113">
<mediaobject>
<imageobject>
<imagedata fileref="images/ISV_Cert_Reg.png"/>
</imageobject>
<textobject><phrase>ISV Cert Reg</phrase></textobject>
</mediaobject>
</informalfigure>
</listitem>
<listitem role="data-line-115">
<simpara>Fill in the required fields and submit the application.</simpara>
</listitem>
</orderedlist>
<simpara role="data-line-117"><emphasis>It will take a couple of days to review the request. Once approved an email will be sent.</emphasis></simpara>
</section>
<section xml:id="_isv_product_integration" role="data-line-119">
<title>ISV Product Integration</title>
<simpara role="data-line-121">We recommend Partner to complete the ISV Production integration process in 2-4 weeks once all the above steps are completed and Partner has received the required credentials to download the binaries(Private cloud)/ access to CDP Management Console(Public Cloud).</simpara>
</section>
<section xml:id="_post_integration" role="data-line-123">
<title>Post Integration</title>
<simpara role="data-line-124">Once the integration between Partner’s software product and CDP Data Platform is tested and validated internally by Partner’s team . Partner needs to work with Cloudera Technical POC to schedule a Demo with Cloudera’s Global ISV certification team. The Cloudera POC will provide necessary information on the topics and other details for this integration demo.</simpara>
<simpara role="data-line-126">After completing this step, Cloudera Team will review the overall integration and will notify the partner if any other details are needed.</simpara>
<simpara role="data-line-129">After the final review from the Global Certification team, the partner will be notified through email.</simpara>
</section>
<section xml:id="_post_certification_of_isv_product" role="data-line-131">
<title>Post Certification of ISV Product</title>
<simpara role="data-line-133">After successful completion of the ISV Certification request, the Partner and Cloudera Technical POC will work together to create a technology blog , GTM highlighting the architecture of the integration and underlying CDP Runtime Version, along with components which were used during this activity.</simpara>
</section>
</section>
<section xml:id="_for_ihv_partners" role="data-line-135">
<title>For IHV Partners</title>
<section xml:id="_validation_tests" role="data-line-137">
<title>Validation Tests</title>
<simpara role="data-line-139">In order to validate the CDP setup, Private Cloud Base or Data Services, we provide a test suite that contains a set of tests to be run and a detailed instruction guide on how to run these. These test scripts generate a result sheet for each test. Once all the tests are run, please share the result sheets along with other metrics that the Cloudera partner team may advise you to note down during the execution of these tests.</simpara>
</section>
<section xml:id="_post_validation_of_ihv_setup" role="data-line-141">
<title>Post Validation of IHV Setup</title>
<simpara role="data-line-143">After reviewing the test results shared by the Partner, the Cloudera team reviews all the results and provides necessary feedback on the same and recommendations to rerun tests, if any test result is not up to the expected benchmark. Once all the results are satisfactory, the Cloudera team confirms the <emphasis role="strong">Field Validation of the CDP setup on the partner hardware</emphasis>. Post this, the Partner and Cloudera Technical POC will work together to create a technology blog, GTM highlighting the hardware configuration, architecture, validation results, and underlying CDP Runtime Version, along with components which were used during this.</simpara>
<simpara><?asciidoc-hr?></simpara>
<simpara role="data-line-147">A technical POC will be assigned to Partner who will help in setting up Cloudera Data Platform
Infrastructure.  It is advisable to run this joint effort as a Project and regular cadence calls with POC and Partner’s team is expected to complete/resolve the issues which appear.</simpara>
<simpara role="data-line-150">Please review the below points to have a better understanding.</simpara>
</section>
</section>
<section xml:id="_appendix" role="data-line-153">
<title>Appendix</title>
<section xml:id="_cdp_private_cloud_base" role="data-line-155">
<title>CDP Private Cloud Base</title>
<simpara role="data-line-157">If you are planning to certify CDP base, then the Cloudera POC will share the guide that contains the steps to install CDP Base , Pre-requisites , and how to enable other mandatory services like Kerberos, TLS,</simpara>
<simpara role="data-line-159">Please note that if you need any help in installing the CDP Base, mention that in the initial discussion with the POC.</simpara>
</section>
<section xml:id="_cdp_private_cloud_data_services" role="data-line-161">
<title>CDP Private Cloud Data Services</title>
<simpara role="data-line-163">If you are planning to certify CDP Data Services, there are a few things that need to be finalized as listed below.</simpara>
<orderedlist role="data-line-165" numeration="arabic">
<listitem role="data-line-165">
<simpara>Hardware requirements for Base</simpara>
</listitem>
<listitem role="data-line-166">
<simpara>Hardware requirements for Private Cloud</simpara>
</listitem>
<listitem role="data-line-167">
<simpara>Security and Authentication mechanism</simpara>
</listitem>
<listitem role="data-line-168">
<simpara>Choice of Container Platform (ECS/OCP)</simpara>
</listitem>
</orderedlist>
<simpara role="data-line-170">Initial discussions with the Cloudera team will be on these points. Once we decide on these, we will proceed with supporting you on the Base installation followed by which we will do a validation of Base before proceeding with the Private Cloud installation. After successful validation, you will get a guide for Private Cloud installation.</simpara>
<simpara role="data-line-172">Once you perform all the steps and are able to successfully register the environment in CDP Private Cloud, you can enable all the Data services.</simpara>
</section>
<section xml:id="_cdp_public_cloud" role="data-line-174">
<title>CDP Public Cloud</title>
<simpara role="data-line-176">The technical POC from Cloudera will assist in setting up an environment on CDP Public Cloud tenant of Partner. Cloudera technical POC will help with the required details and configuration required for the underlying cloud provider. As the underlying cloud infrastructure account is owned by Partner it is expected that Partner will complete all the prerequisites configuration.</simpara>
<simpara role="data-line-178">After the successful registration of the environment of Public Cloud, Cloudera technical POC will guide Partner to enable other PaaS offerings on CDP based on the ISV Certification request submitted earlier. Also the technical POC from Cloudera will assist the Partner’s team in resolving/troubleshooting any technical issues which appear during the integration.(limited to Cloudera Platform).</simpara>
<simpara><?asciidoc-hr?></simpara>
</section>
</section>
</article>